Register of the Shirley Mae Stark papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Printed Matter, 1963-1974 (Box 15-19)
  - Miscellany, 1967-1973, undated (Box-folder 17: 5)
    Excerpt from "Protocol to the Agreement on Ending the War and Restoring Peace in Viet-Nam Concerning the Return of Captured Military Personnel and and Foreign Civilians and Captured and Detained Vietnamese Civilian Personnel," from the treaty "Ending the War and Restoring Peace in Viet-Nam," circa 1973.
    "It Was a Long Time Between Shows: A Former POW Tells How Television Changed During the Years He Was a Captive, Terry, Clifford, TV Guide, July 21, 1973.
  - Newsletters, 1967, 1970, 1973 (Box-folder 17: 6)
    Includes the following: USS Enterprise Family Newsletter, March 10, 1967; Cross Beams, First United Methodist Church, April 1970; Michigan City DeMolayan, circa 1973; and Mig Sweep, Red River Valley Fighter Pilots Association, Spring 1973.
  - Newspapers and clippings, 1966-1978
    Newspapers and clippings collected by Shirley Stark about American POWs in Vietnam and their eventual release. Largely from The San Diego Union and The Evening Tribune, there are also some clippings from other local papers, such as The Coronado Reminder and The Coronado Journal, as well as out-of-state and national newspapers. The bulk of the clippings are from 1973 and cover the return of the POWs and their stories about their time in Vietnam.
    - Chicago Sunday Sun-Times, Viewpoint section, 1973 December 23 (Box-folder 17: 7)
    - San Diego Union, "News in Capsule for Armed Forces,", 1967-1973 (Box 19)
    - San Diego Union, selected articles, 1973 January-April (Box 19)
      Consists of articles from The San Diego Union (and some from The Evening Tribune) about POWs and their release clipped and stapled together by Shirley Stark almost daily from January 23 - April 3, 1973.
    - Vietnam Courier, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 17: 8)
      Four issues: No. 119, July 17, 1967; No. 143, December 25, 1967; No. 164, May 13, 1968; and No. 195, December 16, 1968.
    - William Stark and family, circa 1969-1975 (Box-folder 17: 9-10)
    - Family and friends of POWs, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 17: 11)
    - POW advocacy and support, circa 1969-1973 (Box-folder 17: 12)
      Includes selection of articles about H. Ross Perot and his attempts to deliver supplies to POWs in Vietnam.
    - POW release and return, 1973, 1978 (Box-folder 18: 1-2)
      Includes selected articles about James Stockdale.
    - Vietnam War and POWs/MIAs, general, circa 1966-1974 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Press releases, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 18: 4)
    Selected news releases from the Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense (Public Affairs), as well as one press release from the United States Mission to the United Nations. Other news releases can be found as attachments to correspondence received from the Department of the Navy, Bureau of Naval Personnel.
  - Programs, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Reprints, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    "Excerpts from Remarks by Honorable James D. Hittle, Assistant Secretary of the Navy, Manpower and Reserve Affairs, Navy Federal Credit Union." Original speech delivered August 29, 1969.
    "At Least I Know Jim's Alive," Wylie, Evan McLeod, reprinted from Good Housekeeping Magazine. Original issue date: February 1970.
    "Release and Repatriation of Vietnam Prisoners," Havens, Charles W., III, reprinted from American Bar Association Journal. Original issue date: January 1971.
    "P.O.W.'s Withdrawal Key to Prisoner Release," Hersh, Seymour M., reprinted from Journal-Herald, Dayton, Ohio. Original issue dates: February 13, 15, 16, 17, 18, 1971.
    "Inside the Prisons of Hanoi," Stockstill, Louis R., reprinted from Reader's Digest. Original issue date: April 1971.
    "Greater Love Hath No Man: Eight Years of Commentary on American Prisoners of War and Americans Missing in Action," reprinted from The San Diego Union, 1973. Contains text of articles published in that paper from October 1965 to March 1973.
    "Mystery of Missing GI's," reprinted from U.S. News & World Report. Original issue date: June 18, 1973.
  - Speech transcripts, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 18: 7)
    Includes the following transcripts:
    "Briefing Outline for Remarks by Captain G.E. Hill, Public Affairs Officer, COMNAVAIRPAC, Prestented to the Wives of NAVAIRPAC Naval Aviators Deployed to the Western Pacific," undated.
    "News Briefing, Bethesda Naval Hospital," [news briefing held by returned POWs Lt. Robert Frishman and Seaman Douglas Hegdahl], September 2, 1969.
    "Public Opinion Influences Hanoi - You Are Public Opinion," written by Sybil Stockdale for use by members of the National League of Families of American Prisoners and Missing in Southeast Asia (also includes sample questions and answers and speaking suggestions), circa 1970.
    "Remarks by Admiral Elmo R. Zumwalt, Chief of Naval Operations, at the Navy Luncheon for the National League of Families Navy Next of Kin," September 28, 1971.
    "Challenge My Sermon," Cole, Dr. Edward B., November 7, 1971.
    "When They Return: Plans for PW/MIA Repatriation Detailed," Nutter, G. Warren, 1972.
    "A Service of Thanksgiving and Prayer for Our Prisoners of War and Those Missing in Action," Capen, Richard G., Jr., March 11, 1973.
    "A Shot in the Arm for America," Capen, Richard G., Jr., March 27, 1973.
    Also included is a guide for public speaking engagements for the returned POWs with suggestions of topics to cover.